Leon-Hunter-Public-Portfolio

Click here to download the most recent .pdf

Cloud Native Test Automation Engineer

About

Contact Information

• **Phone**: (302) 312-4489

• **Email**:xleonhunter@gmail.com

• Website:

https://curriculeon.github.io/Curriculeon/

• **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/leon-hunter-3230408b

• Github Organization Ownership

o https://github.com/curriculeon

o https://github.com/git-leon

Education

- Delaware State University (2011 2015)
- Bachelor of Science (BS)
- Computer Science Major, Mathematics Minor

Summary

Experienced T-shaped Engineer and Technical Instructor with a demonstrated history of managing and up-skilling teams of Junior engineers. Highly skilled in Cloud Native Application Development using Java8+, Spring, Mockito, and React JS. Knowledgeable in Cloud Dev Ops using unittest, JUnit5, Selenium, Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes, and AWS. Avid user and advocate of version control management systems, cumulating more than 2500 total Git contributions in the past year. Strong information technology professional with a Bachelor of Science (BS) focused in Computer Science, Mathematics Minor from Delaware State University.

Personal Projects

Owner and Creator

Curriculeon: The Online Coding Curriculum

- Curriculeon is an online curriculum built in Canvas LMS, RevealJs, Jekyll, and Github Pages, which offers free opensource learning content for the following topics:
 - Command Line Scripting

- Version Control Software
- HTML/CSS/JS
- NodeJS. ReactJS
- Java Web Development
- Cloud Computing & Cloud Infrastructure
- Continuous Integration / Continuous Deployment
- Containerization / Orchestration
- Development Operations (DevOps)

Owner and Creator

Leonium.jar: A Selenium and ExtentReport Wrapper Library

- Leonium is an uber jar deployed on package cloud.io that is used to automate Selenium build configuration and script development.
- The library includes an embedded .jar used for dynamically downloading driver binaries
 - This allows this framework to run **GeckoDriver**, **ChromeDriver**, **PhantomDriver**, **HtmlUnitDriver** without downloading any external dependencies
- The library also includes mechanisms for
 - enabling logging for each web-interaction
 - enabling reporting using ExtentReports for aggregating results
 - helper classes with built-in intelligent-waits

Owner and Creator

OpenCVL.jar: An OpenCV Wrapper With Haar Cascade Machine Learning

- OpenCVL is an uber jar deployed on packagecloud.io that is used to ease implementation of Object Detection Algorithm by leveraging OpenCV and HaarCascadeClassifiers.
- The library includes mechanisms for
 - a factory class for dynamically fetching haar cascade classififers
 - face detection interface
 - default face detection implementation with CascadeClassifier dependency injection support
 - face detection builder class
 - face detection factory class

Owner and Creator

JFoot.jar: A Greenfoot Wrapper Library

- Jfoot is an uber jar deployed on package cloud.io that is used to make Greenfoot applications with Maven.
- The library includes mechanisms for
 - converting greenfoot applications to maven applications
 - helper interfaces for building games
 - small gravity physics engine

Owner and Creator

ExceptionalFunctionalInterfaces.jar: A decoration of Java8 FunctionalInterfaces

- Exceptional Functional Interfaces is .jar deployed on packagecloud.io that is used to express code that explicitly throws an Exception, without ever explicitly handling it by defering the try/catch to the respective FunctionalInterface's static tryInvoke method.
- With the advent of Java 8 Lambdas and Method References, functional programming in java has become increasingly popular. Unfortunately, Java 8 does not account for creating lambda expressions which may throw an Exception. This shortcoming has caused a great deal of frustration when developing an exceptional-codebase which should be expressed functionally rather than with object orientation. This library aims to help rememdy the deficiencies of exceptional expressions in Java 8 functional programming.

Experience:

Senior Technical Instructor

ZipCodeWilmington; Wilmington, DE.

May 2021 - Present

- Deliverables include, but are not limited to, the following:
 - Support and lead instructor-led training that prepares students for entry-level careers as a Software Engineers/Developers or as Data Engineers
 - Demonstrate and provide experience with
 - Database management systems, SQL commands, functions, joins, subqueries, and other advanced SQL concepts
 - Full Stack Development with Java8+, JDBC, NodeJS, ReactJS, AngularJS, ExpressJS, JPA, Spring MVC,
 Spring Boot and the like
 - Object-oriented programming, algorithms and data structures
 - Review and debug software code
 - Maintain and update the company's internal LMS with student grades, lab results, testing scores and progress notes
 - Support and maintain the training curricula, syllabi, lesson plans, and any other classroom materials
 - Write content and curriculum related to instructional outcomes, as needed
 - Communicate complex engineering concepts and explain them in an engaging way, as needed

Techpreneur Incubator Lead

ZipCodeWilmington: Techpreneur Incubator Course

March 2021 - May 2021: Wilmington, DE

- Deliverables include, but are not limited to, the following:
 - weekly meetings with techpreneur consultants
 - identification of resources to assist techpreneur consultants with technical development of their products
 - advice, analysis, feedback, and assistance with product development

Remote Lead Technical Instructor

Per Scholas: Cloud DevOps Engineering Course

- Remotely leading a group of 30 aspiring engineers through a Cloud DevOps environment.
- teaching the following topics through live-demonstrations to an audience of 25 in daily Zoom meetings:
 - GitOps, Git, Shell scripting, SQL / DBMS, TDD, Python Scripting
 - Cloud Infrastructure, Cloud Security
 - CI/CD, Nginx, Build Management
 - Deployment and Jenkins Pipeline
 - Docker and Kubernetes
 - AWS Terraform, AWS ECS, AWS EKS, AWS Lightsail, AWS EC2, AWS Cloud9

Remote Lead Technical Instructor

TalentPath: Full Stack Java Engineering Course

November 2020 – December 2020

- Using Git, Zoom, Slack to manage a group of developers through the development of Java Web-applications.
- Leveraged Curriculeon curriculum lectures and curriculum exercises to create an adhoc curriculum to launch learners into an immediately immersive development environment to enforce a deploy-on-day-1 culture.
- Learners receive morning lectures from the curriculum, then exercises from the curriculum to complement the lecture.

Remote Curriculum Developer

Per Scholas: Cloud DevOps Engineering

September 2020 - November 2020

- As a remote curriculum developer, responsibilities included creating content for curriculums which extensively cover the following topics and more over a twelve to fourteen week period:
 - Cloud Security
 - Cloud DevOps
 - Cloud DevSecOps
 - Java8, Spring Security, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, JPA, JDBC, JSPs, Mockito, Git

Remote Lead Technical Instructor

Per Scholas: Full Stack Java Engineering Course

June 2020 - September 2020: Charlotte, NC

- Created more than 65 github repositories, along with branches and configured branching rules, for trainees to leverage to build applications, cumulating more than 500 Git contributions within the organization during the 14 week program.
- Managed the group of developers through the development of more than 20 functioning full stack java applications of developers by utilizing Git and Cloud Native Application Development practices. Application stacks used some variance of the technologies listed below.
 - Java8, Spring Security, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Mockito, JSP, ReactJS, Angular
 - AWS S3, AWS EC2, AWS Cloud9, Heroku, Netlify

Remote Curriculum Developer

Per Scholas

March 2020 - June 2020; Wilmington, DE.

- As a remote curriculum developer, responsibilities included creating content for curriculums which extensively cover the following topics and more over a twelve to fourteen week period:
 - A+ CompTIA
 - Network Security
 - ReactJS, Redux, Node
 - Java8, Spring Security, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, JPA, JDBC, JSPs, Mockito, Git

Lead Software Engineer

Scriptcasters.com: OverseasBasketballConnection.com

January 2020 - May 2020; Wilmington, DE

- Cofounder of Scriptcasters.com, a network of specialized professionals that strive to create innovative technical solutions.
- Hired and lead team of developers to create and maintain a web application and administrative portal for a client seeking a tech solution
- Lead the creation of an application for a client which can connect professional basketball players with overseas teams seeking players, overseasbasketballconnection.com.
- Working alongside one other developer, Frankie Rodriguez, we together created a very successful, popular, heavily used 3-tier platform which
 - allows agents to post job opportunities for players to apply to
 - allows players create a profile and apply for opportunity postings
 - admin portal, which gives client control administrative control over the two aforementioned tiers.
- Including integration testing, deployment, and built configuration, I built the following aspects of the application in their entirety:
 - Java8, Spring MVC, Spring Security, AWS S3, Heroku, Selenium
- The following APIs were leverages for additional features:
 - PrintfulCountry API
 - MailChimp API

Lead Technical Instructor

Per Scholas: Full Stack Java Engineering Course

November 2019 – February 2020; Philadelphia, PA

- Lead Technical Instructor at Per Scholas's Philadelphia pilot of Full Stack Java Engineering bootcamp.
- As lead technical instructor, responsibilities included covering course material via lecture as well as building and testing applications live in front of an audience of 25 developers.

Lead Curriculum Designer

CodeDifferently

July 2019 - November 2019; Wilmington, DE.

- As the Lead Curriculum Developer, responsibilities include technically instructing learners, designing exercises and solutions, as well as managing 3-person development team.
- Created lesson plans, lecture sequences, and architected teaching material via abstractions of reusable content

Lead Curriculum Developer

Zip Code Wilmington: Full Stack Java Engineering Course

December 2018 - May 2019; Wilmington, DE.

- Lead content developer for java programming boot camp.
- Created solutions, lectures, and curriculum for training program.
- Taught Core Java and and Java Web APIs using JDBC, JPA, Spring Boot, and design patterns
- Assisted in the education and job-placement of over 200 junior full-stack application developers

Contractor / Technical Instructor

JPMorgan Chase & Co.

October 2018 – November 2018; Glasgow, United Kingdom

- Contracted through ZipCodeWilmington, served as a technical Java instructor teaching web-development to JP Morgan's incoming, and transitioning developers located in Glasgow, Scotland.
- The course was an intense 12 week training program mocking a real-world developer environment by enforcing collaboration strictly through Github, and enforcing 12 factor configuration methodologies such as leveraging Maven for dependency management and environment variables for application configuration. The course was taught using a stack of Maven, SpringBoot, MySQL, Angular and Heroku

Contractor; Lead Technical Instructor

JPMorgan Chase & Co.

June 2018 - September 2018: Wilmington, DE.

- Contracted through ZipCodeWilmington, I served as the technical Lead Java instructor teaching web-development to JP Morgan's incoming, and transitioning developers.
- The course was an intense 12 week training program mocking a real-world developer environment by enforcing collaboration strictly through Github, and enforcing 12 factor configuration methodologies such as leveraging Maven for dependency management and environment variables for application configuration. The course was taught using a stack of Maven, SpringBoot, MySQL, Angular and Heroku.

Lead Technical Instructor

Zip Code Wilmington

April 2018 - December 2018; Wilmington, DE

• Lead content developer for java programming boot camp.

- Created solutions, lectures, and curriculum for training program.
- Taught Core Java and and Java Web APIs using JDBC, JPA, Spring Boot, and design patterns
- Assisted in the education and job-placement of over 200 junior full-stack application developers

Contractor; **Technical Instructor**

JPMorgan Chase & Co.

June 2017 - September 2017; Wilmington, DE.

- Contracted through ZipCodeWilmington, I served as a technical Java instructor teaching web-development to JP Morgan's incoming, and transitioning developers.
- The course was an intense 12 week training program mocking a real-world developer environment by enforcing collaboration strictly through Github, and enforcing 12 factor configuration methodologies such as leveraging Maven for dependency management and environment variables for application configuration. The course was taught using a stack of Maven, SpringBoot, MySQL, Angular and Heroku.

Technical Instructor

Zip Code Wilmington

April 2017 - April 2018; Wilmington, DE.

- Taught Core Java and and Java Web APIs using JDBC, JPA, Spring Boot, and design patterns
- Covered advanced topics including JDBC, JPA, Reflections, Collections.
- Lectured on design patterns in the context of advanced frameworks such as Spring Boot and Angular.
- Assisted in the education and job-placement of over 200 junior full-stack application developers

Test Automation Engineer

Marlette Funding

January 2016 – April 2017; Wilmington, DE

- Implemented a WebCrawling framework for UI automation scripts and error reporting.
- The application was implemented using Selenium, Selenium Grid, SauceLabs, TestNG, and Extent Reporting.

Undergraduate Researcher

Optical Science Center for Applied Research (OSCAR)

August 2015 - December 2015: Dover, DE.

- The objective of this project was to develop a genetic algorithm to control a spatial light modulator (SLM) used for shaping the profile of a laser beam.
- Implemented evolutionary algorithm for adaptive optics using MatLAB
- Interfaced MatLAB with LabVIEW software.

Operations Leadership Intern

Discover Financial

June 2015 - August 2015: New Castle, DE.

- Implemented BEST QCAS Access Database.
- Manual web tester and bug reporter.
- Implemented Microsoft Word and Excel macros using VBA to partially automate test reporting.

Programming Tutor

Delaware State University

January 2015 - May 2015; Dover, DE.

- Aided learners with completing projects developed in python & java.
- Assisted with understanding of programming logic.

Undergraduate Researcher

National Science Foundation (NSF)

May 2013 - May 2014; Dover, DE

- The objective of this research was to develop a system that would aid in the prevention of catastrophic medical events through persistent intelligent monitoring and early-warning alerting.
- Created interactive electronics using Arduino open-source prototyping platform.
- Coded in C++ to manipulate Arduino microcontroller and eHealth sensor shield.
- Presented research for 2014 Science and Math Investigative Learning Experiences Program (SMILE) Undergraduate Summer Research Symposium.
- Presented at 2014 ERN (Emerging Researchers National) conference.

Programming Tutor

Delaware State University

January 2013 – May 2013; Dover, DE.

- Aided learners with completing programs developed in java.
- Assisted learners with conceptualizing and understanding programming logic.

Project maintained by Git-Leon